shifting Focus to an insurance company
ICI Lombard which reported better than
expected set of numbers motor business
also reported strong growth and to
discuss all this in more and greater
detail we now have gopal balachandran
Chief Financial Officer at ICC Lombard
now joining us thank you so much for
taking your time out and this quarter
numbers were very strong for your
business with operating ratio going down
to about
10.7% and this was largely driven by
loss ratios will the fall in loss ratio
sustain going forward in the next couple
of quarters and can we achieve
10.5% as what was guided earlier by the
management I think the way I would kind
before I specifically respond to it uh I
think I would just kind of uh just uh
reiterate the fact that uh from an IC
Lombard standpoint I think what we have
largely driven as an institution is to
drive uh profitable growth and that's
the reason why we keep looking for
profitable opportunities uh in terms of
how
we want to reselect
portfolios uh the other thing that we
have generally done is uh particularly
in the last few years when the market
has been very very aggressive and
competitive uh in line with our approach
to driving profitable growth we have
stayed cautious on segments which have
kind of been very very aggressive in
terms of outcome um so this is the
reason now when some of those segments
are kind of coming back uh in terms of
growth opportunities from an is lard
standpoint I think we have been able to
reap the benefit of it and you're
absolutely right U I think in general I
think what we have been able to see is
obviously an improvement in our overall
combined ratio numbers but again just
when you look at it on a quarter 3 to
quarter three uh in terms of uh trailing
uh quarters of last year uh the other
thing that you have to keep in mind is
quarter three of last year did have some
impact of catastrophic claims so if I
were to exclude the impact of those
catastrophic claims in Q3 last year the
combined was roughly at about
102.3 uh if you look at the current year
quarter 3 uh the reported combined is
about
102.7 but of course this includes the
impact of the change in regulations
which kind of prescribed on a 1 byn uh
prescription uh so if I were to look at
it on ba basis the combined ratio would
have been largely maintained and that's
the trajectory that we want to take uh
from here on as I said I think the
growth prospects looks quite promising
and therefore the approach of our
combine to continue to see a decline is
something that we are kind of largely
focusing
on the operating ratio to decline
downwards but if you can give us a
number with respect to guidance 10 1.5%
for fi25 is it still
achievable so again if you collect uh I
think this is something that we had
spoken in at the beginning of the year
we looking at how the market momentum uh
is where we had kind of talked about
accelerating the earlier quarter 4
combin that we had thought about ending
at 102 we said we'll be able to
accelerated by another 50 basis points
to 101.5 So to that extent you're
absolutely right but I think again you
have to look at it in the context of how
the market is played outs for example we
have the industry combined ratios uh
which is uh which is one quarter
trailing there if you look at it the
half yearly numbers for the industry
combined is actually wasent uh it was
111% in H of last year it has inched up
to about 113% in H1 of the current year
so we have always maintained that our
movement of combin will be obviously in
the context of how the market uh moves
and hence we will obviously kind of wait
for how the market responds I mean maybe
in the next couple of weeks we will also
have the industry numbers of quarter 3
from there on I think we we will
obviously be able to see whether we are
able to get to that 101. 5% or not but
as we speak I think the trajectory looks
very very positive as I had mentioned in
whether it's in terms of growth whether
it's in terms of our profitability
outcome and if the industry responds uh
in line with expectations there is no
reason for us to not meet the combin of
10 1.5 I think the only caveat that I
would put is uh these days there are lot
of climate change related events and
hence there have been uh unprecedented
increase in catastrophic events so if
something to that extent happens in
quarter 4 it will obviously impact the
industry at Large and it will have
impact us us as well so if you keep that
aside I think pretty much the trajectory
looks
promising out look is quite positive and
10.5% is the guidance and you're
maintaining their guidance but another
segment motor segment it aided growth
for the business in the quarter gone by
this was largely aided by festive season
but is this sustainable what's the
Outlook when it comes to motor segment
going
forward so again if you look at our
thought process which is why I kind of
started off I said that
in the last 2 three years certain
segments were very aggressive motor was
one of them and uh in fact in those
times we actually let go of market share
uh for almost about 2 three years but
now I think we have been able to kind of
recoup some of our lost market share as
we speak I Lombard for motor stands at a
market share of roughly about slightly
more than 11% plus and even if you look
at the growth numbers whether you look
at it on a quarter three or whether you
look at it on a 99 Monon basis I think
we have
relatively decent outperformance Vis the
industry growth numbers uh so we think
again I think all our growth
expectations will be in the context of
market and hence to that extent uh at a
company level not specifically talking
uh in the context of motor at a company
level what we have always maintained is
is Lombard should see in terms of
Topline growth roughly about 100 to 200
basis point alpha or industry growth
numbers so that is where we are because
the reason why I'm saying this is
at different points of time different
segments exhibits uh different outcomes
so hence to that extent I think we
believe we are positively poed to
capture the opportunity for growth
including for
motor so the Outlook as far as motor
segment is concerned is also very
positive but when it comes to return on
Equity it has reached 20% level in the
third quarter higher than what the
management had guided for earlier will
it be fair to assume return on Equity
will remain in the upper band of the
guidance of 16 to 18
% think again all of this have to be put
in context uh if you look at the current
current accounting
prescriptions um I think whatever
Investments that we make on in in
Investments they all come and uh let's
say start hitting Us in the same period
in which those expensing happens uh but
at the same time equally in this
particular in in this particular quarter
and and thereon what you will also
experience is the impact of the change
in guidelines that I spoke about
particularly for long-term policies
where the prescription is to amortise or
recognize the revenues and the cost over
a period of time so hence to that extent
that will also have a factor in so far
as the RO outcomes are concerned and
that that's the reason why we kind of
spoke about more uh ideally Beyond
looking at a particular quarter and More
in terms of medium to long term and
there I think the range that we are
comfortable is uh in that range of 16 to
18% and and more towards the higher
higher end of the range and going
forward if further as I kind of talked
about earlier if the combin ises were to
see a trajectory of improvement then
maybe we will also be able to improve
the Roes but largely We Stand committed
in terms of the range that I kind of
talked about and pretty much on on track
to kind of make it happen committed to
achieving the guidance that's the word
coming in Mr balachandran thank you so
much for taking your time out and
helping us understand what the Outlook
is for the business going forward if you
like this video then like share and
subscribe to ET now